manipalhospitals.com 2019-03-29

# Privacy Policy

### Our commitment to Privacy:

We are committed to protect Privacy rights of individuals whose personal information is provided to us. To affirm our commitment to protect Privacy as well as personal data, we provide this notice explaining our Information Security practices and Policies we follow in collection, storage and use of personal data including sensitive personal data as received from providers under lawful contracts or from persons directly. We ensure all our employees comply with our Privacy and Security policies. Manipal has established its policies, standards and procedures.

### Collection and processing of personal information:

Personal information including sensitive personal data may be received, processed or stored by Manipal only under valid contracts entered into with providers.

The types of personal information received by Manipal may include the following but not limited to: names, addresses of natural persons, as well as sensitive personal data such as password, financial information like Bank account or credit card or debit card or other payment instrument details, medical records and biometric information etc.

 **Accessing or correcting your personal information:** At any time, the provider can request regarding their own personal information maintained at Manipal for various purposes as listed below but not limited to:

  * a.    General information
  * b.    Update of personal information
  * c.    Deletion of personal information

Manipal will respond to such requests as soon as possible after confirming the authenticity of the requestor and the request.

### How to contact us:

Should you as an information provider have any grievances on the data collected, processed or stored by Manipal, you may reach out to the Grievance Officer with questions or concerns about these Privacy policies as follows:

  * a. E-Mail: GrievanceOfficer@manipalhospitals.com
  * b. Postal address: Privacy Officer

The Annexe, #98/2, Rustum Bagh Road, Off HAL Airport Road, Bangalore 560 017 Karnataka | India

Manipal Hospitals Online Privacy Notice Updated Sept 2018. This Online Privacy Notice (“Notice”) describes how Manipal Hospital and its affiliates (“Manipal Hospitals”, “us”, “our” or “we”) collects, uses and shares information from or about you through any online interface (e.g., Website or mobile application) owned and controlled by us (the “Site”, meaning singularly, jointly and severally, any Website or Websites). We will use and share any information that we collect from or about you in accordance with the Manipal Hospitals Privacy Notice (above), which provides choices in the use and sharing of information. When using any of our Sites, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Notice.

### INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE

Personal Information We Collect Online “Personal Information” means personally identifiable information such as information you provide, or that others provide to us on your behalf, via forms, surveys, applications or other online fields including but not limited to name, postal or email addresses, telephone, fax or mobile numbers.

### How We Use Personal Information

We may use Personal Information to:

Respond to your inquiries and fulfill your requests;

Send you important information regarding the Site, changes to our terms, conditions, and policies and/or other administrative information;

Send you marketing communications that we believe may be of interest to you;

Personalize your experience on the Site;

Allow you to participate in surveys, contests and similar promotions and to administer these activities. Some of these activities have additional rules, which could contain additional information about how we use and disclose Personal Information;

Analyze data for our business purposes, such as audits, medical records, enhancing the Site, improving our services, identifying usage trends and determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns; or

Control risk, to comply with laws and regulations and to comply with other legal process and law enforcement requirements.

### Other Information We Collect Online

“Other Information” is any information other than Personal Information that does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an individual, such as:

  * Browser information Online Privacy Policy
  * Information collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies
  * Demographic information and other information provided buy you such as your date of birth; or
  * Aggregated and De-identified Data

### How we protect your personal information

To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with Indian law. These measures include computer safeguards, Data and Database Encrypting,  and secured files and buildings.  

### How We Collect and Use Other Information

We and our third-party service providers, if any, may record, collect and use Other Information in a variety of ways, including:  

Through your browser: Certain information is collected by most browsers, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, device type, screen resolution, operating system version and Internet browser type and version. We use this information to ensure that the Site functions properly and for security purposes.  
Use of cookies: Cookies are pieces of information stored directly on the device you are using. Cookies we use do not contain or capture unencrypted Personal Information. Cookies allow us to collect information such as browser type, time spent on the Site, pages visited and language preferences. We use the information for security purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display information more effectively and to personalize your experience while visiting the Site. We also gather statistical information about the usage of the Site in order to continually improve the design and functionality, to understand how people use the Site and to assist us with resolving questions regarding the Site.

You can refuse to accept these cookies and most devices and browsers offer their own privacy settings for cookies. You will need to manage your cookie settings for each device and browser you use. However, if you do not accept these cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of the Site.

Use of an analytics and optimization service that tracks and analyzes activity on the Site. We use the information for security purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display information more effectively, to continually improve the design and functionality and to understand how people use the Site.

Use of pixel tags, web beacons, clear GIFs or other technologies: These may be used in connection with some Site pages and HTML-formatted email messages to measure the effectiveness of our communications, the success of our marketing campaigns, compile statistics about usage and response rates and to assist us in resolving customers' questions regarding use of the Site.

IP Address: Your IP Address is a number that is automatically assigned to the device that you are using by your Internet Service Provider. An IP Address is identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user visits the Site, along with the time of the visit and the page(s) that were visited. Collecting IP Addresses is standard practice on the Internet and is done automatically by many websites. We use IP Addresses for purposes such as calculating Site usage levels, helping diagnose server problems and administering the Site.

Aggregated and De-identified Data: “Aggregated and De-identified Data” is data we may create or compile from various sources, including mouse clicks and movements, scrolling activity and text you type into the Site. This information is used for business purposes, which may include offering products or services, research, marketing or analyzing market trends and other purposes consistent with applicable laws.

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

 **Social Media Sites**

Manipal Hospital provides experiences on social media platforms such as Facebook®, Twitter® and LinkedIn® that enable online sharing and collaboration among users who have registered to use them. Any content you post, such as pictures, information, opinions or any Personal Information that you make available to other participants on these social platforms, is subject to the Terms of Use and Privacy Policies of those platforms. Please refer to them to better understand your rights and obligations with regard to such content. 

 **Law Enforcement**

If required by law, we may provide any and all information we have about you to law enforcement or other government agencies, pursuant to a subpoena, warrant or other order by a court of competent jurisdiction. Where required by applicable law, we will require written documentation of the request, proof of the identity of the law enforcement official making the request, and we will take steps to authenticate the validity of the request. Any law enforcement or government agency request submitted with less than a court-issued order will be evaluated on a case-by-case basis according to the need and urgency, as well as the particular law enforcement agency making the request. 

 **Links**

The Site may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other websites to which we link. You should also be aware that, when you voluntarily disclose personal information in public forums, such information may be collected by others and may result in receiving unsolicited messages. We strongly encourage you to be aware that when you leave our Site you should read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. 

 **Security**

To maintain the accuracy of the Personal Data, as well as to prevent unauthorized access and ensure the correct use of Personal Data, we have implemented appropriate physical, technical, and administrative measures to safeguard and secure the Personal Data we collect. 

We use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol—an industry standard for encryption over the Internet—to protect in transmission the Personal Data we collect online.  When you type in sensitive information, it will be automatically converted into codes before being securely dispatched over the Internet.  All electronic Personal Data that we maintain in DB is securely stored and further protected through our use of appropriate access controls. 

In addition, to better protect certain Personal Data, some areas of the website channels are inaccessible unless you supply individually identifiable and verifiable information, 

As stated above, in some instances we may entrust Personal Data to third party service providers (including service providers outside of your jurisdiction) upon your acceptance, binding them to protect the security of Personal Data and only to use it for the purposes we specify.   

 **Choice /** **Opt Out**

From time to time, we may send you e-mail, e-mail newsletters or Site news updates alerting you to new features, products, promotions or services pertaining to the Site. If you no longer wish to receive these materials from us you may opt-out of receiving them. We will gladly comply with your requests for removal. Opt-Out Procedure: In compliance with the Can-Spam Act, on each marketing email transmitted by the Site, there are instructions for opting out of receiving future emails. Such instructions may include, without limitation: (a) clicking a link on the email which sends a reply to the sender’s server instructing the server of the sender’s desire to opt out of future emails, or (b) instructions for mailing a written request to be removed from future emails. All requests to opt out of future emails will be respected. 

 **UPDATES TO THIS ONLINE PRIVACY NOTICE**

In the future, we may need to change this Online Privacy Notice or the Manipal Hospital Consumer Privacy Notice. Please review it periodically. All changes will be made here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we may share it with anyone. Any change to a Privacy Notice will become effective when we post the revised Notice on the Site. Your use of the Site following these revisions acknowledges your receipt of the revision and your agreement to and acceptance of the revised Privacy Notice.
